Contact

meetrais@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/raiskazi (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

LLMOps

Attention Mechanisms
BERT (Language Model)

Certifications

Prompt Design in Vertex AI
Generative AI for Everyone
Microsoft Certified AZ-900 Azure
Fundamentals

Amazon Web Services Cloud Practitioner

Introduction to Large Language Models

Publications

Hallucination in Al and Importance of Responsible Al

Debug WCF REST Service.

Simplifying Asp.Net Core Ajax

Consuming Amazon Web Services (SQS, S3) using C#.Net

Website's Shared Count on Social Network

Rais Kazi

Irving, Texas, United States

Summary

Passionate to Digitally Transform Business needs into Software Systems using Art and Science of Solution Architecture.

Experienced Senior Architect with 18 years of extensive experience in Web, Cloud, Mobile, Al, ML, Generative Al & Data applications.

Won new Client and Projects by demonstrating exceptional and proactive work.

Worked on wide range of Technology platforms, tools and programming languages.

Cloud, Generative AI, Data and machine learning enthusiast.

GitHub -> https://github.com/meetrais

Kaggle Profile -> https://www.kaggle.com/meetrais

CodeProject Profile -> https://www.codeproject.com/script/ Membership/View.aspx?mid=4455323

Experience

Cognizant

9 years 3 months

Senior Architect - Technology September 2022 - Present (1 year 9 months)

Dallas-Fort Worth Metroplex

Technology Architect

March 2015 - August 2022 (7 years 6 months)

Washington, District Of Columbia

 Discuss, Analyze and Estimate requirements with Business and Stake holders.

- Participate in MS Azure governance and cost related planning.
- Review and evaluate architecture of existing systems to identify reuse and platforming opportunities as well as refactoring opportunities.
- Lead and coach team members to ensure that programming, design and architecture best practices are followed.
- Drive high priority customer initiatives on Azure in collaboration with customers and companies Sales team.
- Document design and impact analysis of defects and new enhancements.
- Manage code in TFS by branching, labels and merging.
- Coordination with offshore developers for defect fixing and enhancements.
- Integrated MS Azure Services and Azure AI Services.
- Coordination with Azure AD team for application authentication/authorization and Resource Owner/Client Credential flow based authentication for B2B application integration.
- Used technologies such as Web-API, C#, MS Azure, .Net Core, AngularJS, JQuery, HTML 5, SQL Server, SSIS, Visual Studio for development.
- Integrated docusign APIs for digital signature of Loan applications and authorized signatory letters.

Synechron

5 years 3 months

Associate Technology Specialist January 2014 - February 2015 (1 year 2 months)

Lead - Software

January 2012 - December 2013 (2 years)

Spot Award for innovative solution.

Senior Associate

December 2009 - January 2012 (2 years 2 months)

Page 2 of 4

Pune, Maharashtra, India

- 1) Mobile Application Development
- 2) Web Application Development
- 3) Agile Scrum

Ventura

Module Leader

August 2007 - December 2009 (2 years 5 months)

First member to start Dot Net development in Ventura(Capita) India.

Won new Client by demonstrating exceptional and proactive work.

Closely worked with System Admin team to setup Dot Net development environment.

Worked alongside recruitment team to hire Dot Net and UI developers.

Lead and coached development teams to develop multiple web applications.

Architecture, design and development using UML, Visio, .Net technologies and MySql.

Coordination with UK based development team.

"Certificate of Appreciation" For the Year 2007 in Ventura-India Pvt.Ltd.

Zensar Technologies Software Consultant November 2006 - June 2007 (8 months) Pune, Maharashtra, India

Achievements:

1) Spot Award and Team Award winner in Zensar Technologies.

SEED Infotech Ltd Software Engineer July 2006 - November 2006 (5 months) Pune, Maharashtra, India

Extentia Information Technology Software Professional

April 2006 - June 2006 (3 months)

Pune, Maharashtra, India

Ecotech IT Solutions Pvt Ltd (a Weiss GmbH company) Software Engineer July 2005 - March 2006 (9 months)

Pune, Maharashtra, India

Education

University of Pune

Bachelor of Computer Science, Computers · (2001 - 2004)